Speaker 0: It's Monday, July 1st, 2024.
Speaker 0: I'm Rym.
Speaker 1: And I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we're talking about car dashboard technology.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 1: We already got a new month here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a whole new month.
Speaker 0: June feels like it just flew by, but also I've spent a lot of time outside at least.
Speaker 0: A lot of bike rides so far.
Speaker 1: I needed some more June.
Speaker 1: Not enough June.
Speaker 0: The thing is, June had August temperatures, and now it's cooler today, temporarily.
Speaker 0: But biking to and from work has been annoying lately because in New York City, there's really only one good way to bike to my office.
Speaker 0: Biking home, there's two different ways I could go, and the way home is really nice.
Speaker 0: But the way to work, it's pretty much you either take 2nd Avenue or you go way out of your way.
Speaker 1: I still think you could just go... Your work is not far south enough.
Speaker 1: You could just go west, get off the bike, and walk south.
Speaker 0: That would take me about 30 minutes, as opposed to the 12 minutes it takes me to just bike all the way there.
Speaker 1: Walk faster.
Speaker 0: That's New York walk.
Speaker 0: I walk between... Because remember, if you go straight across the bridge and just get off... What's the hurry?
Speaker 0: That's where my... The later I leave for work, the later I can sleep in.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it sucks because biking to work, 2nd Avenue is just destroyed right now.
Speaker 1: They do this, they grind up the street because they're going to repave it, and obviously that's the process.
Speaker 1: And then because New York City streets have so much shit under them, whenever they grind up a street to repave it, they leave it ground up for a while so that anyone who's got to go under the street to do something, utilities, whatever, should theoretically be planning and organizing to do it during that ground up period.
Speaker 1: And then, when they repave it, they'll theoretically have a nice long period before anyone has to cut up the brand new asphalt pavement, whatever, right?
Speaker 1: And so, that's the idea.
Speaker 1: It's a good idea in theory.
Speaker 1: The problem is, is they do not coordinate... In reality, they do not coordinate with all the various agencies and departments and people well enough to get all the work done during the ground up time.
Speaker 1: And so, what inevitably happens is they grind it up, people do some work while it's ground up, they repave, and then someone cuts right into that shit the next week, every single time.
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Where were you last week?
Speaker 1: Is this really an emergency that suddenly appeared that we didn't
Speaker 1: know?".
Speaker 1: But the thing is, when it's ground up in that state, it is awful to drive on and it is even worse to use any other smaller vehicle on because it is just...
Speaker 0: So, like, biking on this stuff, especially because it can be one of two kinds of awful.
Speaker 0: If they grind it horizontally, like perpendicular to the road, to the path you would drive, then it's kind of like a vibrating brrr when you ride over it.
Speaker 0: But if it's angled the other way and you're on a bicycle, then your bike tires are going to be sliding into these little grooves like you're riding your bike on a record, and they're equally bad, but in different ways.
Speaker 0: So one thing that's kind of funny is biking now to work every day.
Speaker 0: A lot of people are just still biking because they have no other way to go, so now bike traffic has resumed on the street.
Speaker 0: But everybody's biking at a glacial pace, and I'd say about a third of the bikers are just biking on the sidewalk and getting into all sorts of kerfuffles.
Speaker 1: -Yeah, of course, yeah.
Speaker 1: -Yup.
Speaker 1: What are they...
Speaker 0: So, I'm just biking in the street, and maybe this is just my mountain biking stuff, but like...
Speaker 1: You keep your ass off the seat so your ass doesn't get destroyed.
Speaker 0: Yup, ass off the seat, and also flexing with the arms.
Speaker 0: So other people are going like three or four miles an hour, because if you go even a little bit fast, the bike's going to be going like fucking crazy.
Speaker 0: I'm going max speed of the e-bike, which is 20 miles an hour, and the bike is just going like crazy, and I'm just treating it like a mountain bike.
Speaker 0: I'm driving faster than the cars on Second Avenue right now.
Speaker 0: But on the way home, I saw something that I've never seen before.
Speaker 0: I've resolved to never tell a bike story again about my commute list.
Speaker 0: I say something I've never said before, and I saw someone ahead of me on the way home, and there's a lot of bike traffic on the Queensboro Bridge.
Speaker 0: So it's not like I'm going to pass this guy, so I'm just going real casual behind him.
Speaker 0: He's wobbling a lot, and I see he's just looking at his phone.
Speaker 0: What he is doing on his phone, he is playing chess.
Speaker 0: He is just straight up...
Speaker 1: I thought you were going to say looking at porn, so that's actually...
Speaker 0: He is straight up playing chess, and putting his full attention on it, while the bike just sort of wobbles back and forth, and I watched him take like seven turns over the course of the Queensboro Bridge.
Speaker 0: I don't think he looked up at any point.
Speaker 0: So I don't know if he was winning that game of chess, but his biking was definitely D-tier, I would say.
Speaker 1: Hey, listen, you know, chess boxing, compared to chess biking...
Speaker 0: Ooh, there'd be a sport, chess biking.
Speaker 1: Chess biking is no problem compared to chess boxing.
Speaker 0: Well, chess biking on Second Avenue in its current situation.
Speaker 1: If you drop your phone, you lose.
Speaker 0: If you drop your phone, you'd better turn around and get it.
Speaker 1: No, here's how the chess biking... Here's how to make the chess biking exciting.
Speaker 1: So you're biking around this area, and there is a chess board in the middle of the area with the pieces.
Speaker 0: Every time you pass the board?
Speaker 1: Right, it's like in order to see the board, you have to bike near it.
Speaker 1: In order to move pieces, you have to bike near it.
Speaker 1: And no fixies allowed, because then you could just sort of try to stay still.
Speaker 1: And if you touch the ground, your opponent, you just lose your next turn every time your foot touches the ground.
Speaker 1: So you have to keep moving around this area.
Speaker 1: So it's like you look at the board, try to memorize it, and then when it's your turn, get back to the board, move your piece, and hit the chess clock.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you're moving, you're doing a drive-by move.
Speaker 1: So if you might move your piece illegally, or move it to the wrong spot, and it's like, well, you let go of it, touch it.
Speaker 1: I guess you could try to go on one pass, pick up the piece, and hold it, and on the second pass, put it down in the exact right spot.
Speaker 1: That could be a good strategy.
Speaker 0: You know, there was a taskmaster once that had something that was... The task made you do a bunch of stuff, but the rule was you have to be on a bicycle the entire time, and your feet can never touch the ground.
Speaker 0: And it was tasked like, go get all these plates and take them to this other table and set them on the table, and then sort these books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: Same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Sort these books that are sitting on a table.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But obviously, you know, a fixie would be cheating, because you would just sort of stay still near the board, right?
Speaker 1: Whoever had the strong legs would win, I guess.
Speaker 0: I would say make it be a mountain bike, because then you could just stand still if you have extreme skills.
Speaker 1: I think the idea is you want to stop the people from standing still to make it more interesting.
Speaker 1: Otherwise the whole game becomes...
Speaker 0: Speed style.
Speaker 0: It's an e-bike that has a minimum speed of three miles an hour.
Speaker 1: It's just always moving.
Speaker 0: It's always moving.
Speaker 0: As a minimum speed, you can pedal, it'll go faster.
Speaker 1: I guess somebody could always bring the rear wheel up into the air and hop on the front wheel and just sort of stay hopping.
Speaker 0: I was about to say that's the mountain biking technique.
Speaker 0: As a mountain biker, I can just hang out on either wheel indefinitely.
Speaker 1: But I mean, I'm saying, it doesn't even have to be bicycle, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe you could do it with a scooter, and both wheels have to be on the ground.
Speaker 1: You think of some way to keep the person always moving.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So in the news, it's not tech news, but it's a big enough deal that we gotta talk about it.
Speaker 0: And the Supreme Court has made a series of catastrophic decisions recently.
Speaker 0: And I don't have time to get into all of them.
Speaker 0: Like, Chevron is already bad.
Speaker 0: The EPA one is already bad.
Speaker 0: But this one is absolutely, like, you know, I'd say shocking.
Speaker 0: But I've lived in America for the last four years.
Speaker 0: Like, it's actually not shocking at all.
Speaker 0: Like, I expected this outcome, which really says a lot.
Speaker 0: The Supreme Court has ruled that the President of the United States has absolute immunity for anything he does in office, even if it's a crime, as long as it's under the color of being an official act of the office.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 1: But the thing what they did not say is they did not say what an official act is and what an unofficial act is.
Speaker 1: So it is still possible, though I don't know how likely, right, that the lower court, or even they could come back to the Supreme Court to answer that question later, would say that, like, you know, only an official act is when you're executing the laws and that's it.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, executing the Constitution within your oath of office.
Speaker 1: And everything else is an unofficial act.
Speaker 1: Or they could say something like, "Yeah, anything the President does is an official
Speaker 1: act.".
Speaker 1: Or they could be like, "Almost nothing the President does is an official--".
Speaker 1: It could go so many ways, right?
Speaker 1: But it is still not great because, you know, we live in a place where we thought we had a rule of law and that all people, even presidents and congresspeople and Supreme Court justices, are subject to the same laws.
Speaker 1: And so, you know, to say that anyone, any human who's a U.S.
Speaker 1: citizen is somehow, you know, different from the other people and in any case, whatsoever, is immune or has some sort of immunity is not cool.
Speaker 0: And it's especially bad for a few reasons.
Speaker 0: So the one thing that's important here is that the Supreme Court right now is fully corrupt in the United States.
Speaker 0: And every vote is basically a 6-3 vote.
Speaker 1: Not all of them.
Speaker 0: There was a unanimous one today.
Speaker 1: It's the ones that are political hotbeds and are a big deal.
Speaker 1: The other ones, like, you know, there was the one today about the-- Social media one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that was unanimous.
Speaker 1: They all agreed.
Speaker 1: Even the bad ones.
Speaker 0: What's tricky here, and this isn't just me spitballing, this is legal scholars saying this exact thing.
Speaker 0: What the court is doing, very obviously and transparently, is the fascist justices on it who are trying to assist the Republican Party in basically their takeover of the U.S.
Speaker 0: government, they are voting on decisions that will help them achieve this goal and giving the wins to the fascist side.
Speaker 0: But they are giving token weak wins on other issues that are related, like they allowed a certain number of emergency abortions in one red state that banned them.
Speaker 0: And those rulings are easily overturned by them again in the future, the way they're structured.
Speaker 0: And they're doing this so that someone who's not super paying attention and doesn't really understand the court, when someone like us or a legal scholar says the Supreme Court is crazy and broken and we're in trouble, they'll look at the news and they'll see, oh, but the court voted yes on these three Democratic things and these four Republican things, so it looks pretty fair to me.
Speaker 0: Like, it's very much a strategy.
Speaker 0: The second thing that an analyst pointed out today, because this just happened, their goal here was very clearly to give Trump as much immunity as possible, but simultaneously not make a ruling that is so obviously catastrophic that the pitchforks come out right now and like the court loses legitimacy to the point that the ruling doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: So what they've done is they ruled on this to give him absolute immunity for official acts, but left a bunch of other questions like the one you pointed out open and then kicked it back down to the lower courts.
Speaker 0: and now, just now, breaking news, while they're handing it back down to the lower courts for the rest of those decisions, they will not do so for 32 days from today because their second clear goal is to ensure that there cannot be any further trials of Donald Trump until after the election, after which point he'll just pardon himself for everything and it's
Speaker 1: over.
Speaker 1: Well, that's okay because they just gave the current president immunity from doing all sorts of crimes.
Speaker 0: Joe Biden could order the Marines to arrest and imprison Donald Trump.
Speaker 1: Well, the question is that he doesn't yet know if that would be an official act.
Speaker 1: and also would the Marines do it?
Speaker 0: I would say he's the commander in chief of the United States military.
Speaker 1: The point is there's a lot of unknowns there, right?
Speaker 1: But the point is there are the illegal things that he could do that could be construed, depending on rulings, as official acts and get away with them to better the nation.
Speaker 1: And if he was not a coward and a weak old man, he would do them immediately.
Speaker 1: I think it's worse than that.
Speaker 1: And he has yet to do so, but he has several months to do so.
Speaker 0: So he has already done this with executive orders.
Speaker 0: He has, I think, pushed through more impactful executive orders than any modern president.
Speaker 0: And he's gotten around a bunch of Supreme Court cases with that.
Speaker 0: But in this case, the problem is I am 100% confident that if Donald Trump or a Republican did something...
Speaker 1: They will immediately do every crime.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But also... They will have no hesitation whatsoever.
Speaker 1: And then they'll just do the crime, whether it's an official act or not, and then be like, "Alright, fight me on it
Speaker 1: later.".
Speaker 1: Even if they're wrong and they lose, it's like, "Well, I did it and it took you this long to do anything about
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: And so that is what the Democrats... You have to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: If they're going to do that, you have to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Just whether it's an official act or not, just do it.
Speaker 1: And if you lose the court case later, it doesn't matter because you did it.
Speaker 1: It happened.
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of the court case later, so I'm pretty confident if Biden actually did anything like this...
Speaker 1: If you're an old man, you're going to die anyway.
Speaker 1: So what do you care if you get found guilty of doing a crime with your unofficial... That's not an official act.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty confident this Supreme Court would fast-track it and immediately rule against him and decide that that specific thing and no other thing is not an official act.
Speaker 1: Well, good.
Speaker 1: Then start doing all the things that Trump is going to do, and then those are all now set as "official act" or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: One way or the other to preemptively prevent him from doing them.
Speaker 0: But this is a big enough deal to where Sotomayor, who is one of the three intelligent people on the Supreme Court who's trying to do the right thing, took the extraordinary step of reading her dissents, which generally doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do it once in a while.
Speaker 0: It's rare.
Speaker 0: It's usually only done when someone has an extreme anger over a decision and basically said that this is like the end of democracy, this kind of decision.
Speaker 0: Like, this is insane.
Speaker 0: Jackson, Katanji.
Speaker 0: Jackson Brown, our newest Supreme Court justice, who is an absolute goat right here, also penned a separate dissent, basically pointing out that... What's the line here?
Speaker 0: The first one, "With fear of our democracy, I dissent," at the end of her 30-page dissension.
Speaker 0: And then Brown basically said, "This breaks new and dangerous ground only to the most powerful official in our
Speaker 0: government.".
Speaker 1: Alright, so they're basically telling, right, the two things that we just said.
Speaker 1: They're telling Biden, "Hey, Biden, the court just decided you have all these powers, please use
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: And they're also telling Biden, like, "Hey, Trump is going to use
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're... I think a takeaway here is that there's a lot of things going on right now, and the US is in a really dangerous place, but...
Speaker 1: The whole world is dangerous.
Speaker 1: Look at what France is doing in their elections, right?
Speaker 0: No, the French elections, so total aside there, how that's gone so far, their elections are really complicated.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to try to explain them.
Speaker 0: I learned them in high school French class.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: They're as complicated as they are.
Speaker 1: They're more democratic than ours.
Speaker 0: I mean, every country in Europe except, like, Hungary and Poland has a more democratic process than us.
Speaker 0: But the way their elections work, after this round, then there'll be, like, more elections.
Speaker 0: Like, they do a really complicated process.
Speaker 0: Basically, the center and the left and the far left parties, like all the people in America would just be Democrats, they are currently coordinating to drop out everyone but one of them in key races.
Speaker 0: Because there are more non-fascists in France who vote than there are fascists, but the non-fascists are split among three or four different major parties, whereas the fascists are all in one fascist party.
Speaker 0: So if the non-fascists can all just agree that we're going to make sure we all vote for one of us in every contested seat, they can still win the government and prevent the fascists from taking power.
Speaker 1: I guess that's necessary because it's not a ranked choice.
Speaker 1: Because if it was a ranked choice, you wouldn't need to do that.
Speaker 1: Because all the voters would just rank all the non-fascists and not rank a fascist, and then it would just happen, you wouldn't need to do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's pros and cons to all those different kinds of votes, but the US left could definitely take a page from that, looking specifically at all the people who, because Bernie Sanders or someone they liked didn't win the Democratic primary, they chose not to vote in the election that determines which power-seeking coalition controls the entire country.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I think the thing I'm going to keep saying is, because we're going to go through a dark time, likely, we knew it was coming, you just feel more dread as you get closer.
Speaker 1: You see a shark out swimming towards you, and you're stuck in the middle of the ocean, and it's just like, you know the shark might come and eat you, and then okay, now I see it's coming straight at me, but it's still a mile away.
Speaker 1: It's like, well now it's a thousand feet away.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, it's not a surprise, but the things I'm going to say and continue to say is that number one, people have lived through dark times before, that doesn't make them good.
Speaker 0: And a lot of people didn't live through them.
Speaker 1: And a lot of people did not live through a dark time, and that is the key, is to, no matter what dark shit happens, stay alive.
Speaker 1: Don't die.
Speaker 1: If you can just stay alive somehow, however you have to stay alive, you're with other people, like us, and other people you don't even know, most people in fact, depending on where you live.
Speaker 1: You can stay, no matter how dark shit gets, is you can stay alive with other like-minded peoples, and have your human life somehow, and there could be a way through, dictators have fallen.
Speaker 0: Well you can take heart in the fact that every time, even going back to Rome, because Roman government at various stages was basically a form of fascism.
Speaker 0: Fascist governments are really good at tearing themselves apart relatively quickly, but not quickly enough for individual humans.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you look throughout history, and it's like, there have been many dark times, including a whole dark age, and it might take longer than your lifetime, who knows, but shit eventually, right, switches the other way.
Speaker 1: So just, to have any chance of seeing that, you just need to stay alive, and then, once you've achieved staying alive, because you can't do anything if you're not alive, you can then put any extra energy you might have towards fighting.
Speaker 1: And then that's it, what else can you do?
Speaker 1: It's like, I can't do, I can vote, the end.
Speaker 0: So speaking of which, if you want to avoid having to internalize what Scott just said, there is a path out of this.
Speaker 0: If Biden wins the election, that buys us at least four more years to try to solve this.
Speaker 1: It is possible for that to happen.
Speaker 0: I would say it is unethical to vote for anybody but Joe Biden in the presidential election.
Speaker 0: You're not choosing what person you want to be president, you are deciding between two power-seeking coalitions.
Speaker 0: One of which is a coalition of almost everybody who isn't a fascist, and the other one is people who will literally kill us.
Speaker 0: Alright, got some tech news.
Speaker 0: Good modern practices for Python development?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Alright, so when you're a computer programmer, no matter what language you choose to do your biz with, there's always a bunch of stuff that is not part of the language itself.
Speaker 1: And when it's actually time to solve real-world problems, you have to bring in libraries, you have to bring in tools, and it's like there might be ten different ways to do a thing, and you don't know which one is the best one.
Speaker 1: And these questions are always in flux, especially with a popular active language.
Speaker 1: The scene is always changing, and what was the best tool yesterday is no longer the best tool.
Speaker 1: And the preferred method of doing something, there might be a new release of the language that has a new technique, and now there's a better way to do a thing.
Speaker 1: And this is what sucks, once you have a big project, it's like trying to update it and keep it, it's like, okay, there's nothing wrong with this code, it's working, but do I bother to put in the effort to rewrite the code or even just small parts of it, or change the tooling to meet the modern best way of doing it.
Speaker 1: Or keep doing it the old way that still works.
Speaker 1: And what even is the current best way?
Speaker 1: That is the tough question.
Speaker 1: You're sitting there with ten different tools to choose from, five different techniques to choose from, what the hell, which one should I pick, they all work, they all do the same thing, which one's the best one.
Speaker 1: So this person wrote an article, and they wrote Python best practices 2024, and I usually, I come across these once in a while, of people basically, you know, zealously saying, these are the ones I like, if you should use what I use, and I'm the right person to listen to.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: And they're all disagreeing with each other, and it makes it even harder for someone who isn't in the know to know what they should be using.
Speaker 1: But this one stood out to me because a large, I'd say over half of the recommendations that they made are things that I was already doing independently, not based on any recommendation, just because, just from experience of trying many different things and landing on a particular thing.
Speaker 0: I'd say the Scott seal of approval is a pretty high bar to reach.
Speaker 1: And so then the other things they recommended that I was not doing, I was like, well, this person's so in line with me on like more than half of their opinions, the things that they said that I'm not doing, I'm going to look into those things.
Speaker 1: And so, yeah, if you are doing any Python programming, I will personally seal of approval these recommendations for the time and the near future until they change again.
Speaker 1: And you'll have to read best practices late 2024 or early 2025 when things are completely different again and you're good.
Speaker 1: Enjoy.
Speaker 0: So in one other little news, uh, you might've noticed, uh, the vision pro apples, uh, a, a pseudo AR VR, uh, headset thingy didn't really get kind of disappeared from all popular discussion pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: Well, it came out, people laughed at it.
Speaker 1: Some people bought it and it appeared like, you know, a couple of times and then people sort of forgot about it.
Speaker 1: Cause it's like you either bought it right away or you didn't buy it at all.
Speaker 1: There's no going to buy it later.
Speaker 0: So, so apparently apple has not given up on this, but
Speaker 1: at WWDC, they talked about it a lot,
Speaker 0: but despite not giving up on it, the
Speaker 1: changes
Speaker 0: they are making to it in terms of how they sell it and features they intend to invest in for it seem to be the worst possible ones to change their situation.
Speaker 0: They're not like pivoting who they're aiming it at.
Speaker 0: They're doubling down on a market that doesn't seem to exist, which is kind of really funny.
Speaker 0: So they seem to be wanting to really double down on people using this for productivity and work and like basically doing zoom meetings.
Speaker 1: It does have some interesting capabilities for that, but it's just impractical and kind of silly and laughable to do that frequently.
Speaker 1: That's like, you know, it's, it's comes across as like, if you were making a movie, the supervillain would be using this to do the zoom meetings.
Speaker 1: It's like not a normal person.
Speaker 0: Cause honestly, like it's replicating the parts of a meeting into the digital space that aren't the ones that are important for most digital kinds of meetings.
Speaker 0: Like when I have most meetings, no one even really needs to see my face.
Speaker 0: They need to hear my voice and they need to see whatever the fuck I got on the screen.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I could talk to Tim Apple, obviously I would talk to him about many other things first.
Speaker 1: If I had to talk to him about this particular product and I could get an honest answer, I would be like, are you using it for your meetings?
Speaker 1: How often?
Speaker 1: I'm sure he has, I'm sure he's has several, at least one in his office, but I'm like, how often are you really using it?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If I get, you know, it's like, it's like, so it's like either a, he's using it a lot supervillain style, which is possible.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or b, uh, he's not using it at all, which basically means deep down inside, he knows.
Speaker 0: So what they are altering their new plan is that they're going to change their in-store demos to show more specific.
Speaker 0: quote deep productivity tasks, like using it to perform some actual task in the store.
Speaker 0: Like they're trying to do longer form demo of something real.
Speaker 0: Uh, they also are dropping the strap they launched with, which apparently was super uncomfortable and providing a much bigger strap.
Speaker 1: That's more like what all, I thought they had like a whole set of straps and that people, the one it came with is super uncomfortable and apparently sucks.
Speaker 0: And now they're going to, now it's going to come with the normal kind that every other VR headset uses because the other companies already solved that.
Speaker 0: It has to go over the top of the head too, or it's uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: And three, they are adding a whole bunch of their AI features to vision OS.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, that's, you know, that's the extent of their tech companies.
Speaker 1: don't, no tech company has any new ideas besides, you know, look at things that come out, which have, you know, which is not much and then jump on them or not.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, an Apple found, you know, an Apple way to incorporate, you know, machine learning with their quote Apple intelligence.
Speaker 1: Some of it was actually, you know, the thing that impressed me that I think was actually good was that the, at the WWDC where they showed the Apple intelligence was the notepad where they were like drawing and doing physics problems.
Speaker 1: Like for, you know, um, that was actually very good.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 0: But I just, I don't think this thing is going anywhere still.
Speaker 1: No, we knew that since it was before it came out that no one would want this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The last thing I want to do is simulate being at work from home rather than just sitting in my comfy environment with screens.
Speaker 0: And if I was going to use this for other types of tasks, I feel like it's not the right hardware for it based on its capabilities.
Speaker 1: I feel like what's happened in a lot of the tech sphere is that people find new technologies and then, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's what, you know, like researchers work on is like new algorithms, new, you know, hardware, things like that.
Speaker 1: And then they're like, okay, we have a new solution.
Speaker 1: Let's go find problems, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There aren't enough people who look for problems and then find solutions.
Speaker 1: And the, and the people who do look for problems and find solutions.
Speaker 1: The problem that the tech world has is that the solutions already exist somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the solutions often aren't even technology.
Speaker 0: This is, this is my day to day life as a product manager.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And, and the thing is, if you're someone who is just a person who takes technology and then builds a solution, like say I am, right?
Speaker 1: Using off the shelf stuff and building solutions, there is work for you to do in this world, solving people's problems with Postgres or web servers or Linux or, you know, RAM, hard drives and CPUs or, uh, cloud services that already exist, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there are already things that exist that you can use to solve most, basically almost everyone's problems.
Speaker 1: And so there's work, that's what most people are working on.
Speaker 1: If you're a tech company selling tools for someone else to solve problems with, you're trying to give me something to use at my work to then solve someone else's problem with.
Speaker 1: It's like, uh, I already sort of have everything I need, bro.
Speaker 1: You know, they need new ideas.
Speaker 1: There are many.
Speaker 1: Really hit kind of a wall.
Speaker 1: The machine learning does solve some problems of certain kinds, but, you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: So as someone who has been a product manager at a global scale for over 13 years now, which is increasingly making me feel old.
Speaker 0: I have found that in my professional experience in capital markets, most problems are not technology problems that require a technology solution.
Speaker 0: Most problems are operational problems, and the solutions to them are usually operational solutions.
Speaker 0: that may involve technology, but building a feature is not how you solve that kind of problem.
Speaker 1: The point is nobody was sitting around saying, "Damn, I got this problem.
Speaker 1: I really just can't figure it
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: And then the Apple Vision Pro came out and they're like, "That solves my
Speaker 1: problem.".
Speaker 1: No one in the earth said that.
Speaker 1: The only person who said that was Tim Apple.
Speaker 0: Tim Apple has a problem.
Speaker 0: I need to make more money.
Speaker 1: I need a new product to look like I actually invent something instead of just coming out with this iPhone with a slightly better camera every year.
Speaker 1: That's the only problem the Apple Vision Pro solved.
Speaker 0: The funniest thing is, so I got a product management certification some years ago, just like work made us all do that, and it was fine.
Speaker 0: Pragmatic.
Speaker 0: So I have the full pragmatic certification, all levels or whatever.
Speaker 0: And its core thesis, this product management framework, the rule one is product management is nothing more than identifying a problem that's out there, coming up with a solution to that problem, and figuring out if you could sell that solution to the people who have that problem.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: And I don't think fucking any company on earth outside of like factories making physical bits thinks that way.
Speaker 1: No, I think that if you look at all the, it's really weird, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there's this huge industry of just like business dogmas and procedures and, you know, systems, you know.
Speaker 0: Just like Sigma, whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: People love to have consultants come to their company and talk to them about agiles and all this sort of nonsense, right?
Speaker 1: You know, and get lessons on stuff.
Speaker 1: But then when they go back to work, they don't ever do anything the person said.
Speaker 1: Or they do, but they only do like part of it half-heartedly.
Speaker 1: Nobody actually does the things the way those consultants say to do them fully, complete buy-in.
Speaker 1: And it's like, and then those things, rightly or wrongly, because they're not all correct, right, get, they're all have this bad reputation of not working.
Speaker 1: And it's like, well, listen, they might not have worked.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to, you know, vouch for any of them.
Speaker 1: But if you didn't give them the honest try of actually truly believing in them and following them, you know, completely, then you're not one to judge whether that shit is real or not.
Speaker 1: And why do you keep hiring the consultants you're not going to listen to?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the part I don't get.
Speaker 0: Because I have been part of consultancy sales to large global financial companies, and they never in my entire life have done anything that we recommend this ever.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I encountered this.
Speaker 0: I was looking around for some high resolution video because I'm thinking about buying a new TV and I want to do some comparisons and whatever.
Speaker 0: And I'm looking like, what 4K content is really out there?
Speaker 0: And I found a channel that has that actually has some 8K content since YouTube.
Speaker 1: YouTube is absolutely loaded with HDRs, 4Ks, 8Ks, high refresh rates, because really, it's the only platform that has supports all those things properly.
Speaker 0: But most of the 8K content I could find was really basically nothing but ads.
Speaker 0: Like, it wasn't actually like real content.
Speaker 0: It wasn't anything interesting.
Speaker 1: It's usually like video of animals and shit like that.
Speaker 0: Pure tech demos.
Speaker 1: Landscapes, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of which, so the one I found that was actually pretty good and I actually did enjoy watching this video, like in the background while I was doing some other stuff.
Speaker 1: See, that's rare, because usually the demo videos are just like these, you know, makes you feel like you're in a Best Buy.
Speaker 1: There's no entertainment value to the head.
Speaker 0: This video is called Small Birds, because birds has all caps, 8K Ultra HD with names and sounds.
Speaker 1: So they're not HDR, though?
Speaker 1: They're just 8K?
Speaker 0: They're just 8K.
Speaker 0: It is just video.
Speaker 0: Very high quality close-up video of cool birds doing their thing, and it tells you what each bird is in case you didn't recognize them, and it's only 20 minutes long.
Speaker 0: It's actually the kind of content I like.
Speaker 0: I like birds.
Speaker 0: I like looking at birds.
Speaker 0: Bird watching is a cool hobby.
Speaker 0: And also, if you have somehow an 8K monitor out there and you want to watch something that's actually 8K, this is one of the few things out there that isn't just a Best Buy, like, eye assault.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 1: What was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Your thing of the day was the arcade cabinet thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, nowadays it's pretty rare for there to be, like, an arcade.
Speaker 1: that's a permanent installation that lots of people go to.
Speaker 1: They're just in certain places in the world, usually amusement areas.
Speaker 1: And even those are not great.
Speaker 1: They're usually full of cranes.
Speaker 1: And the actual arcade machines of the world are usually in someone's house, in a collector's warehouse, at a magfest, right?
Speaker 1: And those are sort of these temporary, either, you know, setups where, like, you know, in order to play, the game's got to be moved and set up, right?
Speaker 1: And moving arcade cabinets really sucks.
Speaker 1: They're, you know, the classic ones are big.
Speaker 1: And, you know, you can't really take them apart.
Speaker 1: There's a big CRT in there.
Speaker 1: It's not a great deal.
Speaker 1: And so when someone rents a truck to bring their games to magfest from their big warehouse, they can only pick and choose a few, right?
Speaker 1: You know, if they bring a Frogger, they can't bring a millipede.
Speaker 1: That's just how it goes.
Speaker 1: There's only so much room in there.
Speaker 1: These people had the job to make some arcade cabinets for some demo games, for some shows, and possibly some other shows, right?
Speaker 1: That would be reused at various, you know, conferences, conventions, you know, whatever, trade shows around.
Speaker 1: And they said, "All right, we want to make full-size arcade cabinets, but we want them to be able to collapse down and be smaller so that we can then ship a lot of them, or ship them more easily in a smaller
Speaker 1: vehicle.".
Speaker 0: I'd say that increases the complexity by an order of magnitude.
Speaker 1: And then set them up again, and, you know, and it's like, "Hey, that's a great idea,
Speaker 1: actually.".
Speaker 1: Because then someone with just like a van instead of a giant box truck could bring, you know, many arcade games to a convention instead of just a few for a lot less, you know, time, effort, money.
Speaker 1: And so they succeeded in doing exactly that.
Speaker 1: They designed and manufactured some collapsible arcade cabinets.
Speaker 1: Obviously not having a CRT helps a lot.
Speaker 1: Obviously not having a whole bunch of old boards and just having modern chips in there helps a lot.
Speaker 1: But even so, it's still, the cabinet itself is still like, you know, full-size.
Speaker 1: It's not like one of those tiny ones you can buy for, you know, your house or whatever.
Speaker 1: So, really good design.
Speaker 1: And I hope people can, you know, if I were to make an arcade cabinet to, say, bring to a magfest with a game that I made in it, I would probably just get this design and make one myself.
Speaker 0: I mean, a big part of that is, I imagine, you'd want to put that in my trunk and then I...
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could just bring it in the trunk, one of them, in the trunk of a car instead of having to rent a vehicle that is capable of hauling.
Speaker 1: That would be kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If I had more space, I absolutely would make a cocktail format cabinet and just have it in my house.
Speaker 1: If I had another room in my house, there would be either...
Speaker 0: I would have one Rampart machine, one Dance Dance Revolution machine, and one...
Speaker 1: That's a big room.
Speaker 0: And one cocktail cabinet if I were rich enough to have space for all three.
Speaker 1: Cocktail.
Speaker 1: I'm not too big a fan of the cocktail ones, honestly.
Speaker 0: Honestly, I like the aesthetic of the cocktail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh yes.
Speaker 1: I would use it as a coffee table.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, you know, if I had enough room, obviously the first priority would be air hockey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: The second priority would be a pinball, a real one, a good one, and then I would get an arcade cabinet and, of course, it would just have every ROM ever with me in there.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't pick one game, but I would put into the control panel all the necessary buttons for, like, every game.
Speaker 1: You know, three trackballs, three joysticks, and I guess I'd do four joysticks and I'd play X-Men.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't go to six.
Speaker 1: That's too many.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 1: No steering wheels.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Let's get right into it because I think we were long enough on the news there.
Speaker 0: So, we drove somewhere recently in my car and Scott got to watch a delicate dance.
Speaker 0: So, modern cars are increasingly putting, we're not talking about anything that drives the car itself directly, none of the, like, controls of the car, but what used to just be a dashboard and a radio, maybe if you were rich in the olden days, like a CD player or a CD changer, like an 8-track.
Speaker 1: Or you swap out and you put a fancy radio in.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But you basically had instruments for the car.
Speaker 0: Then you had the entertainment console, and then you had the heating and cooling console, and they're all kind of in the dashboard, and they were largely uniform and pretty standard for a long time, and they were all extremely dumb, often mechanical devices.
Speaker 1: Until very recently.
Speaker 1: A standard set of symbols, even though each car would be different, and some cars had an up-down lever for temperature where others had dials, but it was still clearly hot, cold, red, blue.
Speaker 1: You'd have the same symbol for a rear washer wiper, or a front wiper, or a defroster.
Speaker 1: They would all have the same symbols, car to car to car, and you could figure it out even if you got to rent a car without having to go to the manual, probably.
Speaker 0: But there was a certain sort of UX of these, partly because of the history of where these instruments came out of, but the UX had to be, you know, like Scott described.
Speaker 0: It has to be intuitive to someone who sits down in any car, anywhere in the world.
Speaker 0: Doesn't matter where you are, the car has to be intuitive enough where you can look at the instruments and immediately or very quickly understand how to use them.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Compare that to, say, an airplane, right?
Speaker 1: Especially a commercial one, where pilots need to have hours and hours and hours of simulator training, and like, you know, on a particular plane to learn the controls of that plane, because it's not the same as the other plane.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: And they have to relearn, and sure, there are a lot of things that are the same plane to plane to plane, because it's still the same core concepts, you know, you still have a stick that goes back and forth.
Speaker 1: But, you know, there's a million, you've seen inside a plane, I'm guessing, and a million switches in there.
Speaker 1: It's like, you got to know what all those do.
Speaker 0: For most of them.
Speaker 0: These constraints in a pre-digital era led to these systems being very simple and having very refined user experiences.
Speaker 0: And the most complex part of any car was the entertainment system in the era where you started to be able to replace them, and you started to be able to try to plug, like, iPods and things into them.
Speaker 0: Ox cables started to appear, and some people put in the fancy ones.
Speaker 0: But now, we've entered an era to where most cars, and we're going to get to a point to where this is all cars, the entertainment system area is replaced by a touchscreen and a shitty computer.
Speaker 0: And these shitty computers are extremely shitty.
Speaker 0: So, we have a Toyota car.
Speaker 1: Not only is the computer itself that is shitty, it is the software for it is shitty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like they just put Windows on these things, or Android, or something that people- Even if they did, that would be a bad idea.
Speaker 0: Yes, it would.
Speaker 1: I think some of them are Android-based, I don't know exactly.
Speaker 0: I mean, there was the Android-based stuff, but it kind of disappeared, and every car I get in is different.
Speaker 0: It's usually by manufacturer.
Speaker 1: It's weird that they're all different, but yet, once I connect, it's the same.
Speaker 0: Well, because they don't use 90% of the stuff in there, because it's all stupid.
Speaker 0: I think that's the key.
Speaker 0: Almost everything that you can do in these screens is stupid.
Speaker 0: And there's a very small number of things people actually use them for.
Speaker 0: Usually, it's playing music, navigating, and if it's a bad car, also controlling the HVAC, if they don't have the HVAC, actually still having separate physical controls, which thankfully, our car has.
Speaker 0: So, our Toyota, the screen with the bad computer in it, is widely regarded to be the best of the car computers right now, based on my research, in that screen- Even better than if you get a Benz, or a BMW, or something?
Speaker 0: From what I've read, they are worse in many ways.
Speaker 1: Interesting, okay.
Speaker 0: But again, this is me reading Reddit, because I was annoyed about a problem I had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's.
Speaker 1: another problem, is how many people have experience with lots of these systems in different cars.
Speaker 1: Usually, car reviewers are reviewing the car.
Speaker 1: There might be someone out there, because I don't read this sort of thing, who's reviewing car computers, but I can't imagine there's that many.
Speaker 1: And when you're buying a car, it's like, if you're a car person who has to buy a car, that's probably not at the most important thing for most buyers, right?
Speaker 0: That was near the bottom.
Speaker 0: We didn't even look at what that thing was capable of when we bought this car, because we literally didn't care.
Speaker 0: We needed a very specific kind of car, and all those extra details were just whatever.
Speaker 0: So, Toyota seems to have the most reliable of them, but even then, our car, one day, not too long ago, this car is brand new.
Speaker 0: Like, it's got under 5,000 miles on it.
Speaker 0: It's the newest software, it's the newest screen, like, it's basically the best you're gonna get in a Toyota.
Speaker 0: And all the Toyota's the same, and I've driven a lot of cars of a lot of different manufacturers and experienced their car computers, because until we bought this car, I rented cars.
Speaker 0: anytime I needed a car.
Speaker 0: So, every time I rent a car, it's a random car, and I got to try it out.
Speaker 0: And one day, we get in the car, we start to drive, and the screen just reboots to black, and then clearly just reboots and starts over.
Speaker 0: And it started rebooting.
Speaker 1: Thankfully, that is not involved in the driving part at all.
Speaker 0: Nope, but it meant, now, instead of navigating where the map and the directions are just being done by the car, now I've got to, like, make my phone loud enough to hear it tell me where to turn, because I can't use this computer screen anymore.
Speaker 0: And the other annoying thing is I can't play music, because every time it reboots, everything stops, even the radio.
Speaker 0: And three, every time it reboots, the screen turns on again, bright white, and blinds me if I'm driving at night, like every 30 seconds in a cycle.
Speaker 0: This was extremely annoying.
Speaker 0: So, we stopped at a rest stop to eat some lunch, and I've kind of given up on this because I can't get it to work, and I go Google it around, and I end up on some Reddits.
Speaker 0: And all I find are people who have the exact same problem with random specific Toyota cars, and the answer is always, I don't know, never fixed it, just gave up, disabled the screen.
Speaker 0: Or, if the car was still under warranty, dropped it off at the dealership and it took them three weeks, and I assume they just physically replaced the entire thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean, that's the real problem, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, it's not an open system that you could, say, repair yourself if you were a computer professional, or even if you took it to a computer professional, they couldn't do it, because it's a closed system.
Speaker 1: And then, if you take it to the dealer, the dealers are auto experts, right?
Speaker 1: They could fix your tires, or your trans suspension, or the engine, it's like, they don't have computer experts at the dealerships with the tools, and knowledge, and service manuals necessary, or anything.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It's like, the only people who could probably fix the problems with those computers are the people who programmed the system, who are probably in Japan, and that's it.
Speaker 1: There's probably no one else on Earth who can fix them.
Speaker 1: And I guess your hope is that they could, they would realize those problems, and then push out, you know, over the air patches somehow, and that would fix it, but other than that, there's really nothing you can do.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's no logs, there's no editing access, there's no troubleshooting, and even if you hack, like, I can get into the dealer menu, like, because, you know, Google around, you'll find ways to do it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't give you any troubleshooting tools that will tell you anything.
Speaker 1: Alright, and so, it's, you know, this is very similar to the smart TV situation, where there's a built-in OS that sucks, you have no control over, you know, if it broke, no one could really fix it.
Speaker 1: But, even on a smart TV, now having a smart TV, you can just disable and ignore pretty much all of that, and use something, you know, I could use the Apple TV, I could use, I could just watch channels with the antenna, I don't actually need to use any of the smart TV functions ever, I could ignore it, block it, and disable it to a great extent, never see the ads it's trying to show, because they're
Speaker 0: blocked,
Speaker 1: and you're still getting full use of the TV, there is no feature of the TV that is essential, that you're not accessing, because you're not using the OS that came with it.
Speaker 1: But if you have a car, it's like, okay, you can drive the car, and in RIM's case, have HVAC, you know, temperature control, climate control.
Speaker 0: I was lucky, if it was a Tesla, that wouldn't have worked.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, navigation, and, you know, I guess you can hear, if you're using your phone instead, okay, but the sound system is not working, because the computer sucks, it's like, that is sort of a core function of the car, that is now not working, and you can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: They're forcing you to bring it in to get it repaired, it's like, no, they can't even repair it.
Speaker 1: It's like, could you imagine, like, my iPhone broke, shit, there's no right to repair, I can't go to a third party, I have to take it to Apple, you bring it to Apple, they're like, yeah, we can't fix that either.
Speaker 1: It's like, buy a whole new car, just because the radio's not working.
Speaker 0: And three weeks, and we might be able to fix it.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like, buy a whole new car, because the radio's not working, or swap out the whole computer in the car, because the mechanic can't possibly, like, you know, flash the OS, or actually investigate it in any way as a computer expert.
Speaker 0: And the funniest part is, some of the problems are caused by the fact that all these systems have basic interfaces, because everyone has either an Android phone or an iOS phone.
Speaker 0: So as a result, Android and iOS each have a "I am talking to a car" feature, that is designed to standardize this.
Speaker 1: The carplay, or whatever Google calls theirs, they're the same thing.
Speaker 0: The problem is, even if that software works, Apple and Android both update that software, but the car people don't update theirs, nor do they even do a lot of QA.
Speaker 1: Right, I mean, this is one of the reasons I believe Apple was trying to make a car, they failed.
Speaker 1: But the one advantage would be that, like, yeah, if they had made a car, then this aspect would have been more acceptable.
Speaker 1: At least if you had an Apple device of some kind, which I assume you would, because who the fuck buys an Apple car and has Windows computers and Android phones?
Speaker 1: Nobody.
Speaker 1: Apple did abandon their plans for the car, it seems, which probably I'm going to assume for good reasons, but I think there was some partnership with Apple and certain car brands that has come and gone at times.
Speaker 1: I think one car brand, I don't forget, recently got rid of it, but I think it would behoove them to either just stop trying to make a fancy car that didn't work, just make a normal car, and do the computer part right, and that will have appeal on its own.
Speaker 1: You don't need to go wild with some nonsense, and find a car brand that will, you know, cooperate with you.
Speaker 0: Harder with you and make a car that just works.
Speaker 0: the way Apple phones just work.
Speaker 1: I walk in, I set my Apple phone down, and then it just works.
Speaker 1: I'm not trying to Apple fanboy here, because I got an iPhone and all Mac devices right now.
Speaker 1: Google, do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Google, go find, like Google and Samsung, right, it's like, go ahead, find a car manufacturer that, you know, you can make a deal with, and be like, listen, we're going to handle the OS for your car.
Speaker 1: You can stop doing it, right?
Speaker 1: We're going to do it, and that will help you.
Speaker 1: just let us do that.
Speaker 1: That'll save you money on development.
Speaker 1: You won't have to do that.
Speaker 1: And two, you will, and then make money, because people will out there will be like, oh, that car has a computer system that doesn't fucking suck.
Speaker 1: Google made it, and Google keeps updating it, and we can trust it a little bit more.
Speaker 1: And Google, how are they going to make money on this?
Speaker 1: Of course, collecting all your data from your car.
Speaker 0: Come on, come on.
Speaker 0: And then Apple will make money by also doing that, but with a veneer of privacy, and charging the company money.
Speaker 1: Apple will make money on it, because it will have very limited features unless you pay the subscription fee to CarCloud.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But I think these are, I would say that sound system is a necessity, and it's dangerous to not have one for people who drive a lot, because one of the main reasons to have a sound system is to put on music or some sort of content to keep yourself awake if you're the kind of person who has to drive a long road trip by yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess so, but I think even more important is simply just traffic and weather information.
Speaker 0: Yep, navigating.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So, I think that I agree, there should be, just like a cell phone that has no service can still call 911, I believe there should be some regulation that requires cars, no matter how busted the computer part is, there should be some AM radio functionality, there should be the base set of functionality that should always work.
Speaker 1: Even if the computer dash thing is like fried, like on fire magic smoke came out.
Speaker 1: And the rest, assuming the rest of the car is still just fine.
Speaker 0: Because I mean, I drove a car six miles without a serpentine belt not that long ago, like cars are pretty durable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, somehow.
Speaker 0: I cannot believe I drove that far.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rym and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowClue.com for show notes, discussion, links, and more.
Speaker 0: Remember, Geek Nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays, gaming and games.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are animation and comics.
Speaker 0: Thursdays are arbitrary and indiscriminate.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: And the Patreon patrons for this Monday episode of Geek Nights on the 1st of July is Alan Joyce.
Speaker 0: R. Alan Joyce.
Speaker 0: Likije.
Speaker 0: Fred Lillie.
Speaker 0: Tenerbra.
Speaker 0: CasecareMatesMusic.
Speaker 0: Chris Sadat.
Speaker 0: Christopher.
Speaker 0: Clinton Walton.
Speaker 0: Finn.
Speaker 0: Penny Reimer.
Speaker 0: Rebecca Dunn.
Speaker 0: Sam Erickson.
Speaker 0: Shervin von Horrell.
Speaker 0: And a ton of people whose names I am not going to say.
Speaker 0: I was trying to think of what to leave you with tonight, and I think an appropriate choice would be...
Speaker 2: I'm sorry, but I don't want to be an emperor.
Speaker 2: That's not my business.
Speaker 2: I don't want to rule or conquer anyone.
Speaker 2: I should like to help everyone if possible.
Speaker 2: Jew, Gentile, black man, white.
Speaker 2: We all want to help one another.
Speaker 2: Human beings are like that.
Speaker 2: We want to live by each other's happiness, not by each other's misery.
Speaker 2: We don't want to hate and despise one another.
Speaker 2: In this world there's room for everyone, and the good earth is rich and can provide for everyone.
Speaker 2: The way of life can be free and beautiful, but we have lost the way.
Speaker 2: Greed has poisoned men's souls, has barricaded the world with hate, has goose-stepped us into misery and bloodshed.
Speaker 2: We have developed speed, but we have shut ourselves in.
Speaker 2: Machinery that gives abundance has left us in want.
Speaker 2: Our knowledge has made us cynical, our cleverness hard and unkind.
Speaker 2: We think too much and feel too little.
Speaker 2: More than machinery, we need humanity.
Speaker 2: More than cleverness, we need kindness and gentleness.
Speaker 2: Without these qualities, life will be violent and all will be lost.
Speaker 2: The aeroplane and the radio have brought us closer together.
Speaker 2: The very nature of these inventions cries out for the goodness in men, cries out for universal brotherhood, for the unity of us all.
Speaker 2: Even now my voice is reaching millions throughout the world, millions of despairing men, women and little children, victims of a system that makes men torture and imprison innocent people.
Speaker 2: To those who can hear me, I say, do not despair.
Speaker 2: The misery that is now upon us is but the passing of greed, the bitterness of men who fear the way of human progress.
Speaker 2: The hate of men will pass and dictators die and the power they took from the people will return to the people.
Speaker 2: And so long as men die, liberty will never perish.
Speaker 0: Soldiers, don't give yourselves to brutes.
Speaker 1: Men who despise you, enslave you, who regiment your lives, tell you what to do, what to think and what to feel, who drill you, diet you, treat you like cattle, use you as cannon fodder.
Speaker 0: Don't give yourselves to these unnatural men, machine men with machine minds and machine hearts.
Speaker 1: You are not machines, you are not cattle, you are men.
Speaker 2: You have the love of humanity in your hearts.
Speaker 2: You don't hate, only the unloved.
Speaker 2: hate, the unloved and the unnatural.
Speaker 2: Soldiers, don't fight for slavery, fight for liberty.
Speaker 2: In the seventeenth chapter of St.
Speaker 2: Luke.
Speaker 0: it is written, the kingdom of God is within man, not one man nor a group of men, but in all men, in you.
Speaker 1: You the people have the power, the power to create machines, the power to create happiness.
Speaker 1: You the people have the power to make this life free and beautiful, to make this life a wonderful adventure.
Speaker 1: Then in the name of democracy, let us use that power, let us all unite, let us fight for a new world, a decent world that will give men a chance to work, that will give youth a future and old age a security.
Speaker 2: By the promise of these things, brutes have risen to power, but they lie, they do not fulfill that promise, they never will, dictators free themselves, but they enslave the people.
Speaker 2: Now let us fight to fulfill that promise, let us fight to free the world, to do away with national barriers, to do away with greed, with hate and intolerance.
Speaker 1: Let us fight for a world of reason, a world where science and progress will lead to all men's happiness.
Speaker 2: Soldiers in the name of democracy, let us all unite!